Catherine Tong

CONTACT Information Wolfson Building Department of Computer Science University of Oxford $\begin{aligned} & \text{Mobile: } +44\ 7984340665 \\ & \text{E-mail: } \text{egctong@gmail.com} \end{aligned}$

Oxford, UK OX1 3QD

RESEARCH Interests Areas: ubiquitous health monitoring, machine learning on graphs, embedding learning of large datasets, multimodal learning.

My current research focuses on developing machine learning models useful for health data analysis. I am interested in using ubiquitous sensing to find connections between people's daily behaviour and health outcomes. In particular, I seek to develop methods which can leverage other resources, including large-scale health records, multimodal sensor streams and graphs (e.g. knowledge graphs and social networks), to overcome the poor data scenarios often resulted from in-the-wild data collection.

EDUCATION

Computer Science, University of Oxford

2017 - 2021 (expected)

Doctor of Philosophy (DPhil), Machine Learning with Healthcare Applications

- Research interests: Machine Learning on graphs, Transfer Learning, Ubiqutous Health monitoring
- Supervised by Associate Prof. Nicholas D. Lane

Physics, University of Oxford

2013 - 2017

Master of Physics, First Class Honours

- Major Options: Theoretical Physics, Atmospheric Physics
- Thesis: Labour Flows on Multiplex Networks
- Other project: Photometric and Evolutionary Analysis of Eclipsing Binary RCMa

AWARDS

Travel Award by the ACM Special Interest Group on 2018
Computer-Human Interaction (SIGCHI)
Examiners' Commendation for Best Practical Work in Physics 2016
College Scholarship for Outstanding Performance in Physics Exams 2013-2017

PUBLICATIONS

[Under Review] Tracking Fatigue and Health State in Multiple Sclerosis Patients Using Ubiquitous Sensing. C. Tong, M. Craner, A. Chieh, O. Bellahsen, M. Vegreville, E. Roitmann, ND. Lane, 2018.

Poster: Inference of Big-Five Personality Using Large-scale Networked Mobile and Appliance Data. C. Tong, GM. Harrari, A. Chieh, O. Bellahsen, M. Vegreville, E. Roitmann, ND. Lane, 2018. The 15th ACM International Conference on Mobile Systems, Applications, and Services (MobiSys '18)

Deterministic Binary Filters for Convolutional Neural Networks. V. Tseng, S. Bhattacharya, J. Fernández Marqués, M. Alizadeh, C. Tong, ND. Lane, 2018. *The* 27th International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence (IJCAI '18)

Multimodal Deep Learning for Activity and Context Recognition. V. Radu, C. Tong, S. Bhattacharya, ND. Lane, C. Mascolo, MK. Marina, F. Kawsar, 2017. Proceedings of the ACM on Interactive, Mobile, Wearable and Ubiquitous Technologies (IMWUT), Volume 1 Issue 4. Also in Ubicomp '18 and MobiUK '18.

Diffusing Workers in a Multiplex World. C. Tong, O. Guerrero, E. Lopez, F. Reed-Tsochas, 2017. *Preprint at SSRN:3056730*.

Work Experience

Nokia Bell Labs, Research Assistant

Cambridge, 06-09/2017

- Trained neural networks for analyzing daily human behavioural data collected with smart mobile and home appliances;
- Analyzed the use of different multimodal deep learning models for activity and context recognition.

University of Oxford, Research Assistant

Oxford, 06-09/2016

Saïd Business School | Centre for Complex Agent-Based Dynamic Networks (CABDyN)

- Formulated and solved a Markov model on multiplex networks to describe the movement of labour across the economy;
- Data analysis and model implementation on UK labour survey data.

Mercer, Consultant Intern

London, 06-08/2015

• Analysis of employee insurance benefits of multinational companies

Poba Software, Project Management Intern

Beijing, 06-07/2014

• Supported in the conception and control of an Office Automation System project

SELECTED ACTIVITIES

Seminar Coordinator at Oxford Women in Computer Science Society

Co-organizer of the 1st Oxford Emerging Tech Party

Mentor at the Oxford Women in Physics Society

Volunteer Tutor at Jacari (providing free home tutoring to children)

Private Tutor in Mathematics and Physics

2017 - present
2018
2014 -2017
2014-2015
2011 - present

ACADEMIC REFERENCES

Nic Lane (nicholas.lane@cs.ox.ac.uk)

Associate Professor, Computer Science, University of Oxford

Eduardo Lopez (elopez22@gmu.edu)

Assistant Professor, Computational and Data Sciences, George Mason University

Joseph Conlon (joseph.conlon@physics.ox.ac.uk) Professor, Theoretical Physics, University of Oxford